

#### Profile

As a student a Virginia Tech, I am consistently learning foundational and technical skills. I have worked on various Web Development projects to improve and learn front end technologies such as React and Redux. I have 2 years of coding experience with Java, and I am proficient with efficient algorithms and data structures. I collaborate well within teams, and learned valuable leadership experience from my school involvements.

## Employment History

#### Extern at AT&T Summer Learning Academy, Virtual

June 2020 — July 2020

- Incorporated professional advice taught by world-class leaders to my personal life and projects.
- Researched and further developed my leadership skills through exercises and modules such as Team Management procedures provided by AT&T.

## President at Teaching Robotics and Engineering, Blacksburg

August 2019 — Present

- Created material relevant to school course materials, in order to ease students into new fields. In turn, collaborated with different disciplines to find the best instructional methods.
- Increased monthly attendance by 20% via the creation of engaging and challenging lessons, and implementation of easy to digest mediums.

# Embedded Systems Member at Martian Subsurface and Analysis Team, Blacksburg

November 2019 — Present

- Implemented researching concepts to practice, with the creation of circuit schematics used for drone prototyping.
- Collaborated with a variety of people from ranging backgrounds to effectively brainstorm and provide creative feedback on the prototyping process.
- Jumped from topics such as Web Socket Programming and Raspberry Pi's to research to ensure that strict deadlines were met.

## Education

### Computer Science (Data Centric), Virginia Tech, Blacksburg

August 2018 — Present

Cumulative GPA: 3.7, In-Major GPA: 4.0.

**Relevant Courses:** 

Software Design & Data Structures, Cloud Software Development, Applied Combinatorics, Intro to Computer Organization, Discrete Mathematics, Linear Algebra, Calculus of Single & Multi-variable

#### Details

1309 University City Blvd APT#3, Blacksburg, 24061, United States, 5715952644

rray18@vt.edu

#### Links

Personal Website LinkedIn Profile

#### **Skills**

Javascript/Typescript

Angular2

React & Redux

Node.js, Express

EJS, Passport.js

Arduino/Raspberri Pi

**Data Structures** 

Java

**MATLAB** 

Python

C++

Solidworks

**G** Suite

Microsoft Office Suite

#### Languages

English

Spanish

Portuguese

#### **Hobbies**

Machine Learning Club at VT DSC Technical Lead Intramural Soccer Fencing Club